Guide to the James A. Kelly collection of Brooklyn firefighting records 1989.006
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 1: Brooklyn Volunteer Fire Department, Western District, 1825-1949
  - Sub-series 1.1: Ledgers, 1825-1934
    - Engine Company 205 (105), Journal, 1914-1919 (Box 227)
    - Engine Company 205 (105), Journal, 1923-1924 (Box 228)
    - Engine Company 205 (105), Journal, 1924 (Box 70w)
    - Engine Company 205 (105), Journal, 1925 (Box 71w)
    - Engine Company 205 (105), Journal, 1926-1930 (Box 228)
    - Engine Company 205 (105), Journal, 1928 (Box 72w)
    - Engine Company 205 (105), Journal, 1930-1931 (Box 73w)
    - Engine Company 205 (105), Journal, 1932 (Box 74w)
    - Engine Company 128 (228), Journal, 1910 (Box 75w)
    - Engine Company 128 (228), Journal, 1910 (Box 211w)
    - Engine Company 128 (228), Journal, 1910 (Box 76w)
    - Engine Company 128 (228), Journal, 1910-1911 (Box 77w)
    - Engine Company 228 (128), Fire record, 1930-1931 (Box 78w)
    - Engine Company 141 (241), Journal, 1911 (Box 202w)
    - Engine Company 141 (241), Journal, 1911 (Box 79w)
    - Engine Company 141 (241), Journal, 1911-1912 (Box 212w)
    - Engine Company 141 (241), Journal, 1912 (Box 80w)
    - Engine Company 141 (241), Journal, 1912 (Box 81w)
    - Engine Company 141 (241), Journal, 1912 (Box 82w)
    - Engine Company 141 (241), Journal, 1912-1913 (Box 83w)
    - Engine Company 141 (241), Journal, 1913 (Box 203w)
    - Engine Company 141 (241), Journal, 1913 (Box 204w)
    - Engine Company 141 (241), Journal, 1913 (Box 84w)
    - Engine Company 141 (241), Journal, 1913-1914 (Box 85w)
    - Engine Company 141 (241), Journal, 1914 (Box 86w)
    - Engine Company 141 (241), Building Inspection Journal, 1904-1910 (Box 206w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1914 (Box 87w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1914 (Box 88w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1914 (Box 89w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1914-1915 (Box 90w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1915 (Box 91w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1915 (Box 92w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1915 (Box 93w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1915-1916 (Box 94w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1916 (Box 95w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1916 (Box 96w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1916-1917 (Box 97w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1917 (Box 98w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1917 (Box 191w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1917 (Box 215w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1917-1918 (Box 216w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1919 (Box 99w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1919-1920 (Box 100w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1920 (Box 101w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1920 (Box 102w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1920-1921 (Box 103w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1921 (Box 104w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1921 (Box 105w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1922 (Box 106w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1922-1923 (Box 107w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1923 (Box 108w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1923 (Box 109w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1923-1924 (Box 110w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1924 (Box 111w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1924 (Box 112w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1924-1925 (Box 113w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1925 (Box 114w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1925 (Box 115w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Journal, 1925-1926 (Box 116w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Fire record, 1922-1925 (Box 117w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Fire record, 1929-1930 (Box 118w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Fire record, 1930-1931 (Box 119w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Fire record, 1931-1932 (Box 120w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Fire record, 1932-1933 (Box 121w)
    - Engine Company 241 (141), Fire record, 1933-1934 (Box 122w)
    - Hook and Ladder 59 (109), Journal, 1908 (Box 123w)
    - Hook and Ladder 59 (109), Journal, 1908-1909 (Box 124w)
    - Hook and Ladder 59 (109), Journal, 1909 (Box 125w)
    - Hook and Ladder 59 (109), Journal, 1909 (Box 126w)
    - Hook and Ladder 59 (109), Journal, 1909 (Box 127w)
    - Hook and Ladder 59 (109), Journal, 1909-1910 (Box 128w)
    - Hook and Ladder 59 (109), Journal, 1910 (Box 129w)
    - Hook and Ladder 59 (109), Journal, 1910 (Box 130w)
    - Hook and Ladder 59 (109), Journal, 1910 (Box 131w)
    - Hook and Ladder 59 (109), Journal, 1912 (Box 217w)
    - Hook and Ladder 59 (109), Journal, 1912 (Box 218w)
    - Hook and Ladder 59 (109), Fire Record, 1909-1910 (Box 132w)
    - Hook and Ladder 59 (109), Fire Record, 1912-1914 (Box 133w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1913 (Box 134w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1913 (Box 135w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1913 (Box 136w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1913 (Box 137w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1913-1914 (Box 138w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1914 (Box 139w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1914-1915 (Box 140w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1915 (Box 141w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1915 (Box 142w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1915 (Box 143w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1915-1916 (Box 144w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1916 (Box 145w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1916 (Box 146w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1916 (Box 147w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1916-1917 (Box 148w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1917 (Box 149w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1917 (Box 150w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1917-1918 (Box 151w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1918 (Box 152w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1919 (Box 153w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1919 (Box 154w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1919-1920 (Box 155w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1920 (Box 156w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1920 (Box 157w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1920 (Box 158w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1920-1921 (Box 159w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1921 (Box 160w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1921-1922 (Box 161w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1922 (Box 162w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1922 (Box 163w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1922-1923 (Box 164w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1923 (Box 165w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1923 (Box 166w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1923 (Box 167w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1923-1924 (Box 168w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1924 (Box 169w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1924-1925 (Box 219w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1925 (Box 170w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1925 (Box 171w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1925 (Box 172w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1925-1926 (Box 173w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1926 (Box 174w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1926-1927 (Box 175w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Journal, 1921 (Box 176w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Fire record, 1914-1915 (Box 177w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Fire record, 1917-1918 (Box 178w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Fire record, 1919-1920 (Box 179w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Fire record, 1920-1922 (Box 180w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Fire record, 1922-1923 (Box 181w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Fire record, 1923-1924 (Box 182w)
    - Hook and Ladder 109 (59), Fire record, 1924-1926 (Box 183w)
    - Hook and Ladder 118 (68), Journal, 1920 (Box 184w)
    - Hook and Ladder 118 (68), Journal, 1929 (Box 227)
    - Hook and Ladder 118 (68), Journal, 1932 (Box 185w)
    - Hook and Ladder 118 (68), Journal, 1943 (Box 227)
  - Sub-series 1.2: Documents, 1856-1949
    - Committee Reports to the Board of Trustees, Brooklyn Fire Department, and Widows and Orphans Fund, Western District, 1856-1863 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Committee Reports, 1864-1867 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Committee Reports, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Committee Reports, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Committee Reports, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Committee Reports, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Committee Reports, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Committee Reports, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Committee Reports, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Committee Reports, 1873-1874 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Committee Reports, 1875-1877 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Committee Reports, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Committee Reports, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Committee Reports, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Committee Reports, 1881-1882 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Committee Reports, 1883-1887 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Committee Reports, 1888-1895 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Committee Reports, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Treasurer's Annual and Quarterly Report to Board of Trustees and Board of Representatives, Brooklyn Fire Department, Western District, 1864-1871 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1872-1879 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1880-1881 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1882-1885 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1885-1886 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Treasurer's Reports (includes some Eastern district info), 1889-1892 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Applications, Resignations and Appointments to Brooklyn Fire Department, Commissions and Boards, 1865-1873 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Bonds for Trustees of the Widows and Orphans Fund, 1875-1892 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Applications, Resignations and Appointments, 1880-1891 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Board Resolutions, includes printed copy of By-Laws, Board of Representatives and Rules and Regulations of the Board of Trustees, Brooklyn Fire Department, 1864-1869 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Board Resolutions, 1870-1872 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Board Resolutions, 1873-1874 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Board Resolutions, 1875-1879 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Board Resolutions, includes printed copies of the Constitution and By-Laws of the Board of Trustees, Widows and Orphans Fund, Western District, 1880-1915 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Board Resolutions, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Board Resolutions, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Board Resolutions, Western District, bills and receipts, mainly Widows and Orphans Fund, incl. some tax bills, 1862-1870 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Receipts and bills, 1871-1873 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Receipts and bills, 1874-1877 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Receipts and bills, 1880-1892 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Board of Trustees, Western District, Contracts for goods and services, mainly Widows and Orphans Fund, 1863-1870 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Contracts, 1871-1874 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Contracts, 1875-1876 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Board of Trustees, Western District, Correspondence, includes correspondence regarding the change to a paid department, 1864-1869 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1870-1879 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1880-1892 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Property Insurance Policies, receipts and related correspondence, mainly on properties owned by or mortgaged to Western District volunteer associations, 1869-1874 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Insurance policies, 1875-1879 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Insurance policies, includes list of insured, 1880-1892 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Ephemera of the Brooklyn Fire Department, Western District, including the Exempt Firemen's Association, late city of Brooklyn, Western District, 1862-1931 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Certificates of service in the Brooklyn Fire Department and certificates of financial need, 1862-1868 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Certificates of Service, 1868-1872 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Amendment to the Act of 1855 of incorporation of the Brooklyn Fire Department Chapter 368 of 1871 regarding eligibility and benefits (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 175 of 1883, an act regarding Cooperative or Assessment Life and Casualty Insurance Associations and Societies (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Brooklyn Volunteer Fire Association Mutual Aid Association certificates of membership, benefits received, death and probate, 1885-1886 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Mutual Aid certificates, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Mutual Aid certificates, 1887 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Mutual Aid certificates, 1887 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Mutual Aid certificates, 1888 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Mutual Aid certificates, 1888 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Mutual Aid certificates, 1889 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Mutual Aid certificates, 1889 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Mutual Aid certificates, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Mutual Aid certificates, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Mutual Aid certificates, 1892 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Mutual Aid certificates, 1893 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Mutual Aid certificates, 1894 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Mutual Aid certificates, 1895 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Mutual Aid certificates, 1910-1929 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Brooklyn Volunteer Firemen's Association, Western District and Exempt Volunteer Firemen's Association, membership cards, receipts, resolutions, pensioner lists, Treasurer's Reports and By-laws, 1890-1933 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Brooklyn Volunteer Firemen's Association, Western District and Exempt Firemen's Benevolent Fund, correspondence (includes near loss of Borough Hall, 1910-1911), and Certificate of Incorporation, Volunteer Firemen's Exempt Association of Brooklyn, Western District, 1910-1949 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Brooklyn Volunteer Firemen's Association, Western District, receipt books, meeting notices, 1914-1923 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Brooklyn Volunteer Firemen's Association, Western District, receipt book, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Papers of John B. Byrne, President and Treasurer Brooklyn Volunteer Firemen's Association, correspondence, speeches, reports, membership lists, 1913-1921 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Papers of J.B. Byrne, 1922-1923 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Papers of J.B. Byrne, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Papers of J.B. Byrne, 1925-1926 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Papers of J.B. Byrne, 1927-1928 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Hook and Ladder Company 109, Property Returns and Accounts, 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Hook and Ladder Company 141/241, Property Returns and Accounts, 1908-1913 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Hook and Ladder Company 141/241, Property Returns and Accounts, 1914-1916 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Series 2: Brooklyn Volunteer Fire Department, Eastern District, 1843-1896
  Arranged chronologically.
  The series contains materials generated by the Eastern District between 1843 and 1896, including badge registers and rosters.
  - Revised Roll, Brooklyn Fire Department, Eastern District (ledger 25), 1843-1869 (Box 54w)
  - Badge Nos. Volunteer Fire Department, Eastern District (ledger 7), 1848-1863 (Box 55w)
  - Register, Brooklyn Fire Department, Eastern District (ledger 26), 1855-1869 (Box 56w)
  - Badge Register (ledger 29), 1857-1866 (Box 57w)
  - Roster of the Volunteer Fire Department Brooklyn, Eastern District (roll) (ledger 175), 1869 (Box 23)
  - Williamsburg (Eastern District), correspondence, 1896 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Series 3: Brooklyn Volunteer Fire Department, Eastern and Western Districts, 1854-1938
  The series contains materials relating to both the Eastern and Western Districts from 1854 to 1938. Included are materials regarding the Firemen's Association, the Benevolent Fund, and the Brooklyn Fire Department. Of special note are the roll of applicants for pensions and the benefits roll, which list the name and address of the recipients, the amount given in pension or relief, and the date of disbursement.
  - Roll of Company of Firemen (ledger 163), 1854-1869 (Box 23)
  - Roster of the Volunteer Fire Department Brooklyn (roll) (ledger 4), 1860-1869 (Box 58w)
  - Information, items of interest, Volunteer Firemen, Brooklyn (roll) (ledger 172), 1858-1869 (Box 23)
  - Ledger, Brooklyn Fire Department Brooklyn (roll and dues accounts) (ledger 13), 1863-1867 (Box 59w)
  - Dues accounts and roll, Brooklyn Volunteer Firemen's Association and Benevolent Fund (ledger 182), 1894-1895 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence and Minutes, Benevolent Fund (ledger 143), 1910-1929 (Box 22)
  - Welwood's List (Treasurer, Brooklyn Volunteer Firemen's Association) (roll) (ledger 171), circa 1915 (Box 23)
  - Minutes, Exempt Volunteer Firemen's Benevolent Fund (ledger 56), 1915-1935 (Box 13)
  - Pensions and Relief Warrants, Exempt Volunteer Benevolent Fund (roll) (ledger 21), 1915-1935 (Box 60w)
  - Roll of Applicants for Pensions and Other Relief to Board of Trustees, Exempt Volunteer Firemen's Benevolent Fund (roll) (ledger 16), 1916-1926 (Box 61w)
  - Benefits roll (ledger 113), 1918-1930 (Box 20)
  - Annual Report to the Board of Trustees, Exempt Volunteer Firemen's Association Benevolent Fund (ledger 20), 1923 (Box 62w)
  - Minutes of the Exempt Volunteer Firemen's Benevolent Fund, Eastern and Western Districts (ledger 104), 1935-1938 (Box 19)
- Series 4: Flatbush Volunteer Fire Department, 1866-1939
  The series contains materials relating to the Flatbush Volunteer Fire Department, dating from 1866 to 1939. Included are roll books, minutes, account books, and correspondence.
  - Roll and Minutes (ledger 154), 1866-1868 (Box 23)
  - Roll, Washington Engine Company No. 1 (ledger 114), 1868-1884 (Box 20)
  - Minutes of the Flatbush Fire Department (ledger 153), 1869-1878 (Box 23)
  - Flatbush Fire Department, correspondence, 1873-1930 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Roll book (ledger 13), 1875-1878 (Box 22)
  - Committee on Supplies (minutes) (ledger 111), 1877 (Box 20)
  - Committee on Supplies (minutes) (110), 1877 (Box 20)
  - Minutes of the Flatbush Fire Department (ledger 98), 1878-1886 (Box 19)
  - Washington Engine Company No. 1 of Flatbush (receipt book) (ledger 158), 1885-1895 (Box 23)
  - Melrose Hose Company No. 2, Minutes (ledger 159), 1885-1887 (Box 23)
  - Washington Engine Company No. 1 of Flatbush (receipt book) (ledger 187), 1885-1895 (Box 24)
  - Melrose Hose Company No.2, Meeting Roll Book (ledger 189), 1886-1887 (Box 24)
  - Melrose Hose Company No.2, Flatbush (dues accounts) (ledger 67), 1887-1888 (Box 15)
  - Dues accounts (ledger 131), 1887-1891 (Box 21)
  - Washington Engine Company, No. 1 (accounts) (ledger 165), 1887-1895 (Box 23)
  - Washington Engine Company, No. 1 (minutes) (ledger 69), 1887-1896 (Box 16)
  - Minutes of the Flatbush Fire Department (ledger 128), 1888-1895 (Box 21)
  - Roll and dues accounts (ledger 92), 1887-1891 (Box 18)
  - Dues accounts (ledger 106), 1889-1895 (Box 19)
  - Malbone Hose Company No. 5 (accounts) (ledger 185), 1889-1896 (Box 24)
  - Carriage Roll Book, Melrose Hose Company No.2 (ledger 132), 1889-1896 (Box 21)
  - Roll and Minute Book, Malbone Hose Company No.5 (ledger 73), 1889-1896 (Box 16)
  - Roll of all Companies (ledger 191), 1889-1938 (Box 24)
  - Dues (ledger 79), 1890-1894 (Box 17)
  - Account book, Dues and Fines, Malbone Hose Company No.5 (ledger 133), 1890-1896 (Box 21)
  - Cash Book and Receipts, Malbone Hose Company No.5 (ledger 150), 1890-1896 (Box 22)
  - Minutes of the Flatbush volunteer Firemen's Association (ledger 51), 1890-1908 (Box 13)
  - Book for Fines, Dues and Assessments, Malbone Hose Company No. 5 (ledger 130), 1891-1895 (Box 21)
  - Washington Engine Company No. 1, Ledger (accounts) (ledger 90), 1892-1895 (Box 18)
  - Dues (Flatbush Volunteer Firemen's Association) (ledger 43), 1892-1902 (Box 12)
  - Dues accounts (ledger 61), 1894-1899 (Box 12)
  - Malbone Hose Company No. 5 (roll) (ledger 190), 1895 (Box 24)
  - Minutes of the Trustees of the Flatbush Volunteer Fire Department and Widows and Orphans Fund (ledger 103), 1898-1916 (Box 19)
  - Dues (roll) (ledger 80), 1899-1906 (Box 17)
  - Dues accounts (ledger 108), 1902-1914 (Box 19)
  - Dues accounts (ledger 74), 1906-1915 (Box 16)
  - Minutes of the Flatbush Volunteer Firemen's Association (ledger 122), 1908-1914 (Box 21)
  - Flatbush Volunteer Firemen's Association (161), 1912-1917 (Box 23)
  - Cash Book-Flatbush Volunteer Firemen's Association (accounts) (ledger 140), 1912-1918 (Box 22)
  - Dues accounts (ledger 65), 1914-1925 (Box 15)
  - Minutes of the Flatbush Volunteer Firemen's Association (ledger 64), 1914-1929 (Box 15)
  - Flatbush Volunteer Firemen's Association (dues accounts) (ledger 63), 1915-1928 (Box 15)
  - Dues accounts (ledger 167), 1917-1935 (Box 23)
  - Flatbush Volunteer Firemen's Association Minutes (ledger 60), 1929-1939 (Box 14)
- Series 5: Gravesend Volunteer Fire Department, 1886-1937
  The series concentrates on items generated by the Gravesend Volunteer Fire Department and includes rolls, minutes, and account books, dating from 1886 to 1937.
  - Records of the Coney Island Fire Department (roll and minutes) (ledger 66), 1886-1903 (Box 15)
  - Friendship Hook and Ladder Company, No. 1, Sheepshead Bay (ledger 82), 1889-1897 (Box 18)
  - Roll, minutes and dues account (ledger 68), 1892-1895 (Box 15)
  - Gravesend Exempt Volunteer Firemen's Association (accounts) (ledger 70), 1899-1914 (Box 16)
  - Widows and Orphans Fund of Gravesend Exempt Volunteer Firemen's Association (accounts) (ledger 118), 1900-1915 (Box 20)
  - Widows and Orphans Fund of the late Volunteer Fire Department of Gravesend (accounts) (ledger 72), 1900-1922 (Box 16)
  - Recording Secretary's Address Book- Gravesend Exempt Volunteer Firemen's Association (roll) (ledger 157), 1902 (Box 23)
  - Minute Book, Gravesend Exempt Volunteer Fire Department (ledger 117), 1902-1906 (Box 20)
  - Sick and Benevolent Fund of Gravesend Exempt Volunteer Fire Department (accounts) (ledger 112), 1902-1922 (Box 20)
  - Gravesend Exempt Volunteer Firemen's Association Honorary Members (106), 1906 (Box 23)
  - Minutes for Gravesend Exempt Association (ledger 94), 1913-1922 (Box 18)
  - Minutes for Gravesend Exempt Association (ledger 40), 1922-1937 (Box 14)
  - Roll Book (ledger 137), undated (Box 14)
- Series 6: New Lots Volunteer Fire Department, 1866-1949
  The series concentrates on materials relating to the New Lots Volunteer Fire Department, including roll, minute, and account books dating from 1866 to 1949.
  - Liberty Hose Company No. 1 (roll and dues) (ledger 148), 1866-1875 (Box 22)
  - Minute Book (ledger 144), 1867-1872 (Box 22)
  - Account Book (ledger 95), 1872-1874 (Box 18)
  - Roll and Minute Book (ledger 105), 1872-1880 (Box 19)
  - Roll book, Alert Pump and Bucket No. 1 (ledger 146), 1875 (Box 22)
  - Day Book (accounts) (ledger 127), 1875-1885 (Box 21)
  - Minutes of the Franklin Engine Co., No.2 (ledger 142), 1876-1881 (Box 22)
  - Roll book and dues accounts, Franklin Engine Company, No. 2 (ledger 147), 1876-1883 (Box 22)
  - Roll book (124), 1876-1885 (Box 21)
  - Supply Committee (minutes) (ledger 101), 1877-1884 (Box 19)
  - Roll Book of Fire Department, New Lots (ledger 10), 1879-1886 (Box 63w)
  - Minute Book, Liberty Hose and Bucket Company No. 1 (ledger 97), 1880-1883 (Box 19)
  - Roll and dues account (ledger 188), 1880-1884 (Box 24)
  - New Lots Fire Department Minute Book (ledger 96), 1880-1885 (Box 18)
  - Franklin Engine Company No. 2 (accounts, dues, committee lists) (ledger 164), 1881-1882 (Box 23)
  - Roll book (ledger 129), 1882-1886 (Box 21)
  - Roll book, Franklin Engine Company No. 2 (ledger 138), 1883-1885 (Box 22)
  - Record of fires and alarms (ledger 121), 1884 (Box 21)
  - Financial Accounts of Franklin Engine Company No. 2 (ledger 126), 1884-1886 (Box 21)
  - Minutes and Miscellaneous Accounts of Franklin Engine Company No. 2 (ledger 120), 1884-1886 (Box 21)
  - New Lots Volunteer Firemen's Association, certificate of incorporation, 1886 (Box 7, Folder 5)